Three weird sisters met in the day of success,
and I have learned by the perfectest report that they have more in them than mortal knowledge.
When I burned in desire to question them further, they made themselves air, into which they vanished.
Whilst I stood rapt in the wonder of it came missives from the king,
who all-hailed me 'Thane of Cawdor,'
by which title, before, these weird sisters saluted me, and referred me to the coming on of time
with 'Hail, king that shalt be!'
Hail, king that shalt be.
This have I thought good to deliver thee, my dearest partner of greatness,
that thou might’st not lose the dues of rejoicing,
by being ignorant of what greatness is promised thee.
Lay it to thy heart, and farewell.”
Macbeth.
Glamis thou art,
and Cawdor;
and shalt be what thou art promised.
King of Scotland.
Yet I do fear thy nature; It is too full o' th' milk of human kindness to catch the nearest way:
thou wouldst be great, Art not without ambition, but without the illness should attend it.
What thou wouldst highly, that wouldst thou holily;
wouldst not play false, and yet wouldst wrongly win.
Thou'ld’st have, great Glamis, that which cries, “Thus thou must do,” if thou have it,
And rather thou dost fear to do, than wishest should be undone.
Hie thee hither, that I may pour my spirits in thine ear and chastise with the valor of my tongue
All that impedes thee from the golden round,
a crown.